Before we go back to our motion model and how we can simplify
モーションモデルに話を戻し 状態同士の関係を簡単にし
the relations between the states and to give them values,
それらに値を与える方法を見る前に
I want to introduce the first order Markov Assumption.
一次マルコフ仮定を紹介しようと思います
Assume you want to estimate the posterior distribution
前の状態で与えられた p xt の
of p x_t given our previous states,
事後分布を推定するときに
and you have no observations or controls.
観測やコントロールがない場合を想定します
So this is a pretty simple example but it works fine to explain the Markov Assumption.
これは非常に単純な例ですが マルコフ仮定の説明に適しています
You can write this distribution as
この分布は
the following: This relation can be represented as a chain.
次のように「関係の連鎖」として書くことができます
For example, to estimate or predict x_1,
たとえば x_1 を推定または予測するには
we only use x_0.
x_0 のみを使用します
To estimate x_2, we use x_1 and x_0.
x_2 を推定するには x_1 と x_0 を使用します
And finally, for x_3,
そして x_3 には
we use x_2, x_1, and x_0.
x_2 x_1 x_0 を使用します
In this example, the Markov Assumption postulates that x_2 is the best predictor for x_3.
この例では マルコフ仮定は x_2 が x_3 の最良の予測子であると仮定します
This means, that the other states, x_1 and x_0,
つまり その他の情報 x1、x0 は
arts or future states, carry
x3 をより正確に予測する上では
no additional information to predict x_3 in a better way far more accurately.
何も追加的な情報をもたらしません
We also say the state x_2 is complete.
これで状態 x2 は完了です
We remove the links or connectors between x_1 and x_3,
x_1 と x_3
and x_0 and x_3,
x_0 と x_3 の間のリンクまたはコネクターを外します
which means x_3 is independent of x_0 and x_1,
つまり x_3 は x_0 と x_1 とは関係がなくなり
it only depends on x_2.
x_2 のみに依存します
And of course, for x_2, it is the same.
もちろん x_2 についても同じです
This means, you can also remove this guy over here.
つまり ここのこれも外すことができます
Since we now assume,
今 ｘt が前の状態にのみ
that x_t only depends on the previous state,
依存していると仮定するので、事後確率を
we can rewrite the posterior in this way.
このように書き換えられます
So, if we want to continue this chain,
よってこの連鎖を続けるには
which means to predict the future,
つまり将来を予測するには
we only take x_3 into consideration.
x_3 のみを考慮します
An example could be a weather forecaster,
天気予報士を例に挙げることができます
the weather of tomorrow only depends on today and
明日の天気は今日のみに依存し、
today includes our previous information and is uncertain, of course.
今日には以前の情報が含まれ、それらはもちろん不確定です
As an important fact,
重要な事実として、x0には仮定値を置いている
we have to assume that we have an initial guess for x_0.
ことを考えなければなりません
So, x_0 must be initialized correctly.
そのため x_0 を正しく初期化する必要があります
Let's go back to our motion model and I will show
では モーションモデルに戻って マルコフ仮定から
you how we can benefit from the Markov Assumption.
どのような利点が得られるのかを見てみましょう
Before I talked about the Markov assumption,
マルコフ仮定について説明する前に
I stopped here and ask you,
ここでみなさんに尋ねたいと思います
how we can simplify the structure?
どうすればこの構造をシンプルにできるでしょう？
Now, I will show you how the Markov Assumption can help us here.
では マルコフ仮定がここでどのように役立つのかを説明します
First, I split the control vector into the current control,
まず 制御ベクトルを現在のコントロール
u_t, and our previous controls.
u_t と以前のコントロールとに分けます
Now, let's take a look to the first term,
では 最初の項を見てみましょう
the probability distribution of p x_t is conditioned by x_t minus one,
p xt の確率分布は xt - 1 と すべての以前の
all previous observations or controls, and the map.
観測またはコントロールと マップで条件付けされます
Here, we apply the Markov Assumption the first time,
ここで初めてマルコフ仮定を適用します
since you already know x_t minus one,
皆さんは既に xt - 1,
set one_to_t minus one,
z1:t - 1, u1:t, で xt が良い方法で
and u 1_to_t minus one will not carry
予測するための追加情報を
additional information to predict x_t in a better way.
持たなくなることはご存じです
These values were already used to estimate x_t minus one.
これらの値は既に x_t マイナス 1 を推定するために使用されました
This means, x_t is independent of these values.
つまり x_t はこれらの値とは関係がありません
Because of this fact,
このことより
we can remove these two conditions in the graph.
グラフのこれらの 2 つの条件を削除できます
This will result in the following,
この結果 次のようになり
and the posterior distribution of x_t only depends on x_t minus one,
x_t の事後分布は x_t マイナス 1
u_t, and the map.
u_t およびマップにのみ依存します
This term is called,
この項は 遷移またはシステムモデル
the transition or system model,
と呼ばれ 予測をしたり前の状態を
which predicts or which moves the previous state in the new one.
新しい状態に移したりします
And as you can see,
そしておわかりのとおり、
we do not need the whole observation or control history.
全体的な観測と制御の履歴は共に不要です
Here, you can also consider that the map,
さらに、ここで マップ m は
m, does not influence x_t.
xt に影響しないと考えることができます
It is common practice to neglect m,
m を無視することはよく行われますが
but here, we keep it.
ここではキープしておきます
The second term describes a posterior distribution of x_t minus one,
2 番目の項は 以前のすべての観測またはコントロール およびマップが
given all previous observations or controls, and the map.
提供された場合の xt - 1 の事後分布を表します
Here, we use a Markov Assumption again.
ここでもう一度マルコフ仮定を使います
We assume that u_t tells us nothing about x_t minus one,
ut は将来のことであるため ut は xt - 1 について
because u_t is in the future.
何も示さないと仮定します
We ignore u_t to estimate the state,
状態 xt - 1 を推定するのに ut は無視し
x_t minus one, and we move this condition over here.
この条件をここに移動します
Based on this assumption,
この仮定に基づいて
we rewrite the motion model again.
モーションモデルを再度書き直します
After these two steps,
これらの 2 ステップ後
we achieved a really, really important step.
非常に重要なステップを実現しました
I ask you, do you know why?
どうしてかわかりますか?